Part 3. You will hear two veterinary science students called Diana and Tim
discussing their work placements and their course modules. First you have some
time to look at questions 21 to 26.
Now listen carefully and answer questions 21 to 26.
So Tim, we have to do a short summary of our work experience on a farm. Right, my
farm was great but arranging the work experience was hard. One problem was it
was miles away and I don't drive and also I'd really wanted a placement for a
month but I could only get one for two weeks. I was lucky the farmer let me stay
on the farm so I didn't have to travel but finding the right sort of farm to
apply to wasn't easy. No, they don't seem to have websites do they? I found mine
through a friend of my mother's but it wasn't easy. No. My farm was mostly
livestock, especially sheep. I really enjoyed helping out with them. I was up
most of one night helping a sheep deliver a lamb. On your own? No, the farmer
was there and he told me what to do. It wasn't a straightforward birth but I
managed. It was a great feeling to see the lamb stagger to its feet and start
feeding almost straight away and to know that it was okay. Then another time a
lamb had broken its leg and they got the vet in to set it and he talked me
through what he was doing. That was really useful. Yes, my farm had sheep too.
The farm was in a valley and they had a lowland breed called Suffolk's, although
the farmer said they'd had other breeds in the past. So were they bred for their
meat? Mostly, yes. They're quite big and solid. My farm was up in the hills and
they had a different breed of sheep. They were Cheviots. Oh, I heard they're wolves
really sought-after. Yes, it's very hard-wearing and they use it for carpets.
Right. I was interested in the amount of supplements they add to animals' feed
nowadays. Like, even the chickens got extra vitamins and electrolytes in their
feed. Yes, I found that too and they're not cheap. But my farmer said some are
overpriced for what they are and he didn't give them as a matter of routine
just at times when the chickens seemed to particularly require them. Yes, mine
said the same. He said certain breeds of chickens might need more supplements
than the others but the cheap and expensive ones are all basically the
same. So did your farm have any other livestock, Diana? Yes, dairy cows. I made a
really embarrassing mistake when I was working in the milkshed. Some cows had
been treated with antibiotics so their milk wasn't suitable for human
consumption and it had to be put in a separate container. But I got mixed up
and I poured some milk from the wrong cow in with the milk for humans so the
whole lot had to be thrown away. The farmer wasn't too happy with me. I asked
my farmer how much he depended on the vet to deal with health problems. I'd read
reports that the livestock's health is being affected as farmers are under
pressure to increase production. Well, he didn't agree with that but he said that
actually some of the stuff the vets do, like minor operations, he'd be quite
capable of doing himself. Yeah, my farmer said the same but he reckons vet skills
are still needed.
Before you hear the rest of the conversation, you have some time to look
at questions 27 to 30.
Now listen and answer questions 27 to 30.
Now we've got to give a bit of feedback about last term's modules, just short
comments apparently. Shall we do that now? OK, so medical terminology. Well, my heart
sank when I saw that, especially right at the beginning of the course and I did
struggle with it. I thought it would be hard but actually I found it all quite
straightforward. What did you think about diet and nutrition? OK, I suppose. Do you
remember what they told us about pet food and the fact that there's such
limited checking into whether or not it's contaminated? I mean, in comparison
with the checks on food for humans, I thought that was terrible. Hmm, I think
the module that really impressed me was the animal disease one, when we looked at
domesticated animals in different parts of the world, like camels and water
buffalo and alpaca. The economies of so many countries depend on these but
scientists don't know much about the diseases that affect them. Yes, I thought
they'd know a lot about ways of controlling and eradicating those
diseases but that's not the case at all. I loved the wildlife medication unit,
things like helping birds that have been caught in oil spills. That's
something I hadn't thought about before. Yeah, I thought I might write my
dissertation on something connected with that. Right, so actually I was thinking
something along the same lines.
That is the end of part three. You now have half a minute to check your answers
to part three.